The other library I just want to do a quick show and tell
demo on is, if you haven't heard of this, this library
ViewUse is a phenomenal library.
It is a bunch of wrappers around basically browser APIs.
So things that you might commonly want to do say, I
don't know, you want to be able to do something with a clip
board?
This should look familiar.
It says, oh, this is a use clipboard function that we
can import.
And when you import it, it'll actually basically copy over
whatever it is as a v-model and whatnot, and it just works.
And so to show you just as a show and tell on this, something
that we often want to do when it comes to apps is use local
storage.
And if you've never done that from scratch, it's a pretty good
API to use, but there is a bit to do as far as manually
configuring that in addition to managing reactive state.
So one of my favorite functions is the use storage here with
Pinnier.
So if we look at Pinnier use storage with ViewUse, you can
see that ViewUse.
OK, here we go.
This is a blog post that actually shows how it would work.
So basically, if I scroll down here, you'll notice that
inside of this to-do list, you have this one line right here
that allows you to import from use storage.
And what it does is basically creates that local storage
key, and then every time it's being updated, when Pinnier
loads, it will know with ViewUse's help to check the local
storage first to see if there's new data.
If there's already existing data, it'll actually start from
the local storage and not from this initialized value.
And so what you end up getting is this really elegant
coming together of your ViewUse functionality with your
reactive data inside of your ViewApp.
And so other ones that are really fun that you might
want to check out as well is the color preference, like
color mode.
And so what you see here is that what this is doing is that
it's basically a reactive property that allows you to
easily toggle the state of the theme of your app.
There's so much stuff in here because basically what they've
done is taken a bunch of browser APIs and made it really
easy to integrate inside of your ViewApp.
So definitely highly recommended as one to check out.
The other final thing that I want to shout out is regarding
transitions in View.
So as we know, creating good user experiences, that's a
really important part of making things
easier for users to follow.
And so we don't have time to go into detail on this, but
basically there are built-in components called
transition and transition group that help you manage how
things are being attached as they exit.
So the most common example that I'll show right now, because
you can check out the docs, the one that I love to show is
the one for transition group, because this is the one that
I think we do a lot.
So if I go down into transition, transition group, a lot
of us render lists.
Rather than have them blink in like this, you can also have
them move in a way that's even smoother.
You see here, this actually allows you to shuffle stuff.
And all that is being done, how?
It's being done by wrapping basically your component
inside of this transition group.
There's a little bit of CSS that happens there, but I'll
leave you to check out the docs to get inspiration from
that.
But just know that this is built into the library so that
if you want to try playing around with it, making the
users easier to track things.
This is also where the keys are very important, because as
you can see, we're doing things like shuffling here.
View needs to be able to know which element it is, where it
needs to go as it's moving stuff around.
So this is another bit that if you all are developing for
your apps, definitely check out the transition group and
transition for ways to enhance your user experience.